The ball is back!
Phantasm II is a action, horror, science fiction
film directed by Don Coscarelli.
Mike, after his release from a psychiatric hospital, teams up with his old
pal Reggie to hunt down the Tall Man, who is at it again.
A mysterious, beautiful girl has also become part of Mike's dreams,
and they must find her before the Tall Man does.
Mike, played by James LeGros.
Reggie, played by Reggie Bannister.
The Tall Man, played by Angus Scrimm.
Liz, played by Paula Irvine.
Alchemy, played by Samantha Phillips.
Father Meyers, played by Kenneth Tigar.
Phantasm II is a 1988 American science fantasy horror film written and directed by Don
Coscarelli and stars Angus Scrimm, James LeGros, and Reggie Bannister.
It is a sequel to Phantasm (1979) and is the second
installment in the Phantasm franchise.
The plot follows the first film's protagonist, Mike Pearson, who is recently released from a mental
institution, recruits his friend Reggie and some new friends in an effort to defeat the Tall Man.
The film caused controversy among fans by recasting main character
Mike with LeGros, and was not well received by critics.
It was followed by two direct-to-video sequels: Phantasm III: Lord of the Dead (1994) and Phantasm IV: Oblivion (1998) as well
as the final film in the Phantasm franchise: Phantasm: Ravager (2016), which received a theatrical release.
Following distribution problems in the U.S., Phantasm II was released
in Region 1 on DVD in 2009 and Blu-ray disc in 2013.
The film explores themes of portal, undertaker, evil, tall man, sentinals.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.